A Guide to the Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection, 1924-1956
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection, 1924-1956
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1990-057
9.8 cu. ft. 2 boxes; 28 oversize folders
The Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection includes drawings for residences, schools, churches and businesses primarily located in southern California. In addition to Olive Chadeayne’s work, the collection also contains over twenty-five drawings by American architect Lillian Rice.
Olive Chadeayne, 1904-2001; Rice, Lilian, 1889-1938
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in multiple accessions between 1990 and 1994.
Alternate Form Available
The Digital Library and Archives Imagebase contains 20 digital images from the Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection. Projects include photographs, blueprints and tracings arranged by project.
Imagebase
Biographical Note
Olive Chadeayne
Olive Chadeayne was born on February 9, 1904 in Ossining, New York. Educated in California, Chadeayne began studying architecture at the University of California (currently UCLA) in 1922 later completing her coursework at Berkeley when the UCLA architecture program was shut down. Chadeayne graduated with a B.A. in Architecture from Berkeley on May 12, 1926 and went on to complete her graduate work there in 1927.
Los Angeles based architecture firm, Pierpont & Walter Davis hired Chadeayne shortly after graduation in 1927. During the time Chadeayne spent at the firm she worked on a number of small residential projects improving her drafting abilities. In 1935 Chadeayne met and became close associate to architect Lilian J. Rice (1888-1938). For three years Chadeayne collaborated with Rice, designing two schools, small offices and other assorted buildings. Their association was cut short when Lilian Rice passed away suddenly in 1938, Chadeayne went on to complete a number of Rice's unfinished work projects.
In 1940 Chadeayne began taking on private contract work for the first time and accepted a teaching position at Cornell University. There, she taught house planning in the College of Home Economics. By July 1942 however, Chadeayne returned to California taking work as a production illustrator for the Lockheed engineering department in war service. While working for Lockheed Chadeayne also handled side projects for various firms in the Los Angeles area concentrating primarily on residential and educational facilities. In 1945 Chadeayne left Lockheed.
By 1951 Chadeayne was hired at Daniel, Mann, Johnson & Mendenhall (DMJM). Her job at the company required extensive travel to educational facilities in various stages of building development. As a result of her travels, Chadeayne became a highly skilled specifications writer for DMJM. Her ability to write technically became her greatest professional asset.
“I tried to write specifications so that the ordinary workmen could understand them. I found that the specifications were the standard by which the building was built and that some of the workmen couldn’t understand…So I tried to write them in a way that anybody could…”
From 1958 to 1965 Chadeayne worked at Los Angeles based firm, A.Q. Jones & Frederick Emmons. She worked on a number of projects including a U.S. Air Force hospital, Naval housing and most significantly, the U.S. Consulate in Singapore. By 1966 one of Chadeayne’s most prominent architectural endeavors began when she was hired to write specifications at the Bank of America Headquarters in San Francisco, California.
By 1970 Chadeayne retired formally but continued working part time until 1973 as a consultant for renowned architecture firm, Skidmore Owings & Merrill (SOM). There she wrote furnishing specifications for a bank project in Buffalo, NY.
Throughout her career and in retirement Chadeayne held membership with the AWA (Association of Women Architects) and the Los Angeles chapter of the AIA (American Institute of Architects). Chadeayne took an active in role in AIA serving as chairwoman for the membership committee and later on the Codes Committee ensuring utilization of California building regulations statewide.
In her free time Chadeayne enjoyed cooking and gardening. She spent significant time traveling with friends and family visiting such places as Australia, New Zealand, China and Japan. She died on February 23, 2001 at the age of 97 in Tracy, California.
Works Consulted
Chadeayne, O., Horton, I. S., O'Hara, E., International Archive of Women in Architecture, & American Institute of Architects. (1993). Olive Chadeayne, architect: Transcript of an oral history interview with Inge Horton and Elizabeth O'Hara for the International Archive of Women in Architecture, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University and AIA San Francisco, a chapter of the American Institute of Architects. S.l: s.n.
Horton, Inge Schaefer. (Eds.). (2010). Early women architects of the San Francisco Bay Area: the lives and work of fifty professionals, 1890-1951. Jefferson, N.C: McFarland & Co. Inc.
Lilian Rice
Lilian Rice (1889-1938) was born in National City, California in 1889. She attended the University of California at Berkley for architecture and in 1910 became one of the first females to graduate from the program. Rice’s greatest professional achievement came from her work as resident architect in the design of the upscale southern California community, Rancho Santa Fe.
Recognized for her work with Spanish colonial architecture, Rice advocated utilizing natural and local materials to blend surrounding landscapes into her designs. This practice was particularly evident in her work on the Rancho Santa Fe community.
“Every environment here calls for simplicity and beauty: the gorgeous natural landscapes, the gently broken topography, the nearby mountains. No one with a sense of fitness, it seems to me, could violate these natural factors by creating anything that lacked simplicity in line and form and color.”
In addition to her work on the Rancho Santa Fe community, Rice designed San Dieguito Union High School in Encitas, California later serving as an original trustee for the Rancho Santa Fe school district.
Lilian Rice died suddenly on Dec. 22, 1938 at the age of 49.
Works Consulted
Cox, Lilian. (2009, October). Famous female architect finally gets a biography. The Coast News. Retrieved from http://thecoastnews.com/view/full_story/3901797/article-Famous-female-architect-finally-gets-a-biography
Eddy, L. L. (1985). Lilian Jeannette Rice: The lady as architect (A University of San Diego Thesis By Lucinda Eddy). University of San Diego, San Diego, CA.
Scope and Content
Summary
The Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection spans the year’s 1924 to 1956 with the majority of projects completed in greater southern California. Additionally, the designs of architect Lilian J. Rice are included. This collection contains both independent and collaborative design projects by Chadeayne and Rice.
Materials in the collection include watercolor drawings, tracings, blue prints photographs, magazine clippings and display boards for approximately 125 projects. The collection is divided into three series.
Series Breakdown
Series I: Personal & Professional Papers (1924) consists of Chadeayne’s student work; watercolor designs; portrait photographs of Chadeayne as well as her co-worker, Greta Grossman; and magazine clippings from Ladies Home Journal.
Series II: Project Records (1926-1952) includes project notes, finished project photos, display photos and Chadeayne’s drawings.
Series III: Art & Artifacts (1927-1937) contains, one watercolor drawing of the Townley residence and one historical color map of Monterey, California.
Arrangement
There are three series in The Olive Chadeayne Architectural Collection. Series I: Personal & Professional Papers and Series III: Arts and Artifacts are arranged chronologically according to project. Series II: Project Records, is arranged alphabetically by client/project title. Blue prints are stored separtely from tracing and dizao papers. Blue line/diazo drawings are stored with tracings, separted by interleaving tissue.
Index Terms
Persons:
Olive Chadeayne, 1904-2001.; Rice, Lilian, 1889-1938.
Subjects:
Architectural drawing--20th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings.
Occupations:
Architects.
Local Subjects:
International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA).
Contents List
- Series I: Personal & Professional Papers.
  Scope and Content
  Series I: Personal & Professional Papers (1924 - 1925) consists of Chadeayne’s student work. It includes watercolor designs, portrait phototgraphs and magazine clippings from Ladies Home Journal.
  - 30 magazine clippings (interior/exterior designs; undated; Ladies Home Journal). (Box-folder 1-1)
  - 31 magazine clippings (Interior/Exterior Designs, undated; Ladies Home Journal). (Box-folder 1-2)
  - 2 Black & White Portraits (unknown location; undated; Olive Chadeayne (front) - Gretta Grossman (back)). (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Classical Columns in Watercolor/Ink (Berkeley, CA; January - April 1924; Student Work - 8 sheets drawing/painting paper; Olive Chadeayne). (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 1 Folder 1)
  - Religious Buildings and Ferry Terminal (Berkeley, CA; c.a. 1925; Student Work - 13 sheets drawing/painting paper (untitled works) & 1 sheet (ferry terminal drawing); Olive Chadeayne). (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 1 Folder 2)
- Series II: Project Records.
  Series II: Project Records (1926-1956) includes work completed by both Olive Chadeayne and Lilian Rice. The series contains architectural tracings, blue prints, drawings, project notes and photographs for approximately 100 projects.
  Arrangement
  The following is a list of architectural projects carried out by Olive Chadeayne and Lilian Rice. The Project Index is a way to organize the various formats of architectural records from the same collection. The index is arranged alphabetically by project/client name and contains information, when available, about the location, date, project type, lead architect and additional collaborators.
  Project Index Key
  Project/Client Name (location; date; project type; architect; collaborator(s)) [Format: DR=Drawings, FPP=Finished Project Photo(s), DP=Display Photo(s), AA=Arts & Artifacts, F=Files (project files)]
  Project Index
  - Adams (undated; Tracy, CA; Residential; unknown architect) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 22)
  - Bevis (Tracy, CA; undated; residential; architect unknown)[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 21, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 20, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 28)
  - Block D Residences/First Unit of Residences (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1926; Commercial/Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 32 Folder 25, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 3)
  - Browder/Piper (Encitas, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 10)
  - Burroughs (La Jolla, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 6)
  - Caldwell (Carlsbad, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Campbell (Del Mar, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC32 Drawer 13 Folder 6)
  - Carmichael (1937; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 6)
  - Casebeer (Glendale, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 18)
  - Cavenee (San Diego, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 18)
  - Chadeayne, Mr. & Mrs. U.G. (Van Nuys, CA; 1927; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 25, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 4)
  - Chadeayne, Mrs. & Olive (Sherman Oaks, CA; undated; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Chadeayne, Olive (Van Nuys, CA; 1938; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9)
  - Chadeayne, U.G. (Van Nuys, CA; undated; Residential – Photos; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP]. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Comstock (unknown location, CA; undated; Residential; unknown architect) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 23)
  - Cramer (Studio City & Van Nuys, CA; undated – 1945; Residential – Photographs,Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP][DP][DR]. (Box-folder 1-3, Box-folder 2-1, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Crosby (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 11)
  - Davis (Solana Beach, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 8)
  - Deane (Corona Del Mar, CA; 1951; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 21)
  - Details of Plank Structural Floor (Montgomery Country, MD; undated; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Eubank (Encitas, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Exclusive Flower Shop; Remodeling of Shops at 6th Ave. & B St. Façades - Preliminary Elevations (San Diego, CA; undated - 1940; Commercial – Drawings and Photograph; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP][DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 27, Box-folder 1-5)
  - Francisco - Remodeling of Rancho Santa Fe Store; and Garage (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938; Commercial/Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.))[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 11, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 12)
  - Fletcher (Pacific Beach, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne(assoc.))[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 11)
  - Frank (Solana Beach, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne)[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Full Size Frame Details (uknown location; 1940; unknown; Olive Chadeayne)[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Gabriel (Encitas, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Garage Wing (Tracy, CA; undated; Drawing; architect unknown) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Good - Residence & Guest Cottage at Beach House (Rancho Santa Fe & Del Mar, CA; 1938 - 1940; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 7, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Griffin (Van Nuys, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 18)
  - Hotchkiss (Tracy, CA, 1947; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Johannes - Boys Room & Bath; and Proposed Garage Addition (Tracy, CA; 1945 - 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 18, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Johnston (Encitas, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 8)
  - Killen (Ocean Beach, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Kinney (Del Mar, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Kirby (Encitas, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 16)
  - Kitchen Elevations - north, south, east & west (unknown location; undated; Drawing; architect unknown)[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - La Jolla Building & Loan Co. - Residence & Garage & Commercial Building (La Jolla, CA; 1937 - 1940; Residential & Commerciall; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 5, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - La Jolla Federal Savings & Loan Co. - Residence & Service Building (La Jolla, CA; 1938; Residential & Commercial; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 7)
  - Lamplugh (Encitas, CA; 1939; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 12)
  - Larrick (Solana Beach, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Lemcke (Patterson, CA; 1949; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 20)
  - LeMontree (San Diego, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9)
  - Lindenschmidt (Del Mar, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Lineweaver (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1940; Residential & Project Notes; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 16)
  - Lunch Shelter for Rancho Santa Fe School (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938; Institutional; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 10)
  - Market Building, Mushet Construction Co. (Del Mar, CA, 1939; Commercial; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 12)
  - Martinet (Tracy, CA; 1947; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Matthews (Tracy, CA; 1948; Residential, Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - McGrew (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 12)
  - Miller (Encitas, CA, 1939; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 13)
  - Moore (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 16)
  - Mooreshead (La Jolla, CA; 1948; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Morton (La Jolla, CA; undated – 1939; Residential – Photos & Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP][DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 14, Box-folder 1-4)
  - Naftzger (Del Mar, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 6)
  - Novak (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938 - 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 26, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 12)
  - Office Shop and Building (Tracy, CA; Commercial - Photograph; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP]. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Pardy Job, Mushet Construction Co. (unknown location; 1938, Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 11)
  - Peto (Vista, CA; 1939; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Physics and Chemistry (unit D-4), Art Rooms and Store for San Dieguito High School (Encitas, CA; 1937; Institutional; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 25)
  - Portion Lot 5, BLK 17, Map 142 Street Measurements (unknown location; undated; Commercial; unknown architect) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Proposed Auditorium for San Marcos Elementary School (San Marcos, CA; 1940; Institutional; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 13, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 26)
  - Proposed Episcopal Church (Del Mar, CA; 1938; Religious; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 10)
  - Reconstruction of Rancho Santa Fe Elementary School (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1931 & 1940; Institutional; Lilian Rice & Whitsitt (assoc.) & Olive Chadeayne ) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 27, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Remington (San Diego, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Residence (incomplete) (La Jolla, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 10)
  - Revised Kitchen (unknown location; undated; Drawing; unknown architect) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Roberts (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Savage (Solana Beach, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9)
  - Schiebel (Pacific Palisades, CA; 1956; Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 21)
  - Schloessman (Del Mar, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 11)
  - Sectional Thru Steel Beams (unknown location; undated; Drawing; architect unknown) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawe 15 Folder 22)
  - Shield, Plan of Flat Floor Hall for Pasadena Civic Auditorium (Pasadena, CA; 1932; Institutional; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 25)
  - Shindledecker (Solana Beach, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9)
  - Siegfried (Del Mar, CA; 1940; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 15)
  - Signage (unknown location; undated; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 28)
  - Sonnenberg (Tracy, CA; 1948; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 19)
  - Spalding (Del Mar, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 7)
  - Stephens (Solana Beach, CA; 1939; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 13)
  - Stratton (Van Nuys, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 18)
  - Strawn (unknown location; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 28)
  - Streett (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1941; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 17)
  - Sutherland (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1938; Residential; Lilian Rice) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 9)
  - Theis (Pacific Palisades, Huntington Palisades & Los Angeles, CA; undated – 1950; Residential - Photographs, Display Photographs & Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [FPP][DP][DR]. (Map-case Drawer 15 Folder 28, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 21, Box-folder 2-2, Box-folder 1-5)
  - Townley (Del Mar, CA; undated – 1936; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.) ) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 3, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 26)
  - Tyson (Del Mar, CA; undated - 1936; Residential; Lilian Rice & Olive Chadeayne (assoc.)) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 13 Folder 3, Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 26)
  - Underhill (Rancho Santa Fe, CA; 1946; Residential; Olive Chadeayne)[DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 14 Folder 18)
  - Unidentified Directions/Suggestions for Residence (unknown location; undated; Project Notes; unknown architect) [F]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan, Mushet Construction Co. (unknown location; undated; Drawing; architect unknown) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan (unknown location; Aug. 28, 1940; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan (unknown location; undated; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan (unknown location; undated; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan (unknown location; undated; Drawing; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Rafter Plans (unknown location; undated; Drawing; architect unknown) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 28)
  - Unidentified Residence Sketch, Mushet Construction Co. & O’Brien (unknown location; undated; Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Unidentified Residence, Structural Sheets 1-5 (unknown location; undated; Drawings; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 22)
  - Unidentified Residence & Floor Plan (unknown location; undated; Residential; Olive Chadeayne) [DR]. (Map-case MC 32 Drawer 15 Folder 23)